*OPEN BGM*
在一个没有开源的世界里
In a world without open source,
来自未来的执法者
enforcers from the future
穿越时空去摧毁
travel back through time to destroy
Linus Torvalds 的计算机
Linus Torvalds's computer.
*Saron Yitbarek的尖叫~*
*起床声*
天啊 我又做了那个噩梦
Oh, man. I had that nightmare again.
在梦里 我有一些很棒的想法
The one where I've got these amazing ideas,
但我不能上手开发
but I can't develop them
因为没有相应的开源技术可以使用
because there's no open source tech to work with.
我认为一个没有开源的世界几乎注定是邪恶的
I think a world without open source is almost bound to be evil.
我想 如果软件在 20 世纪 80 年代遭到闭源
If software had been closed in the 1980s and
（LCTT 译注：这里的软件指 MINIX）
而源代码再也没有被开源过
and the source code had never been opened up again,
肯定会少很多创新
I think that there'd be a lot less innovation for sure.
那将是一个落后的世界
It would be a backward world.
*BGM~*
我认为智能冰箱肯定会变得更少
I think there'd certainly be less smart refrigerators.
*BGM*
*在一个没有智能冰箱的世界中*
*In a world without smart refrigerators.*
*BGM*
好吧 好吧 你懂的
Okay, okay. You get the point.
我们正在想象一个没有开放源代码技术的世界
We're imagining a world without open source technology,
这并不特别美好
and it's not very appealing.
想象一下：
So picture it.
它们无处不在
Gatekeepers at every part of the road.
于开发者而言
For us developers,
没有开源的世界
a world without open source
意味着更少的自由和影响力
would mean far less freedom—and influence.
*BGM*
在整整一季中 我们一直在纪录开发人员在开源世界中的角色
All season long, we've been tracking the role of developers in an open source world.
随着开源技术与工具的不断涌现
Our work has been evolving and expanding
我们的工作也不断演进和扩展
with the growth of the open source tools and techniques that make our work possible.
无论是敏捷宣言 DevOps 的兴起 还是容器编排
Whether it's the Agile Manifesto, the rise of DevOps, or container orchestration,
我们宣称的力量和自由
the power and freedom
都与开源哲学紧密相关
is tied to that philosophy of open source.
在本季的最后一集
In our season finale,
我们将会回顾前几集中的内容
we're taking a step back and looking at how far we've come.
随着世界走向开源
As the world goes open source,
这个词的原始含义能剩下多少呢？
how true to the original meaning of that term can we remain?
而我们 接下来 则将何去何从
And where are we headed next?
*BGM*
我是Saron Yitbarek 这里是《代码英雄》
I'm Saron Yitbarek, and this is Command Line Heroes.
一款红帽公司原创的播客节目
An original podcast from Red Hat.
*BGM*
第 7 集：开启未来
Episode 7: Days of Future Open
*BGM*
没有开源的世界不是我想要的世界
A world without open source is not a world that I would want to live in,
也不是绝大多数人想在其中生活的世界
nor do I think that it is a world that the vast majority of people out there would want to live in.
这位是史蒂文·沃恩-尼科尔斯
This is Steven Vaughan-Nichols.
你可能在第一集和第二集里
You might remember him from Episodes 1 and 2
谈论操作系统战争的时候记住了他
when we were talking about the OS wars.
他是哥伦比亚广播集团互动媒体公司的特约编辑
He's a contributing editor at CBS Interactive
从快速调制解调器的速度还是 300 比特每秒时以来 他就一直关注着科技
and he's been following tech since 300 bits per second was a fast modem.
除了 Linux 之外你可能无法叫出任何一个开源程序的名字
You may not be able to name a single open source program other than Linux,
但是你当前的生活是建立在开源之上的
but you're current life is a life built on open source.
如果不使用开源技术 绝大多数人甚至无法上网
Most of us can't really go online without using open source tech.
开源技术几乎存在于地球上的每台超级计算机中
It's in almost every supercomputer on the planet.
它运行在物联网物联网（IoT）中
It's running the Internet of Things.
它存在于你的手机、你的 Web 服务器，你的社交媒体
It's in your phone, your web server, your social media,
以及 大型强子对撞机中
and oh yeah, it's running the Large Hadron Collider, too.
并非只有我们开发者从中受益
And we developers aren't the only ones who've figured out the benefits of this stuff.
开源态度现在已经超越了技术的范畴
Open source attitudes are now spreading beyond technology
影响了其它行业 例如经济学、音乐、科学和新闻业
to influence other industries like economics, music, science, journalism.
如果建筑师
What if an architect
以我们分享代码的同样方式
shared the blueprint for a building
分享建筑的蓝图
in the same way we share code?
如果一个记者打开她的档案
What if a reporter opened up her files
让任何人不仅可以检查她发表的文章
and let anyone scrutinize not just her published article,
还能检查她的研究和采访记录
but her research and interview notes?
我们不应为此而惊讶
It shouldn't surprise us,
因为开发人员培育这份哲学已有多年
the philosophy that developers have been nurturing for years.
每个人都可以
he idea that everyone gets to
看到代码、注释代码、复制代码、提供补丁
see and comment on the code, copy it, offer fixes,
这实际上是一件非常基础的事情，对吧？
it's actually a pretty fundamental thing, right?
这就是共享
It's sharing.
自最早的人类分享食谱以来
Ever since the earliest humans were sharing recipes for meals,
我们就知道公开分享指令集
we've known that openly sharing sets of instructions,
或者说算法 对人类是净收益
algorithms in other words, has a net benefit for humanity.
在某些方面
In some ways,
开源技术现在能使我们重温这个基本事实
open source technologies are now allowing us to get back to that basic truth.
我认为 使更多的事物开源
I think that more things being open source kind of facilitates
会促进和鼓励人们查阅原始资源 这总是很好的
and encourages people to go back and consult primary sources, which is always good.
这位是 Hannah Cushman
That's Hannah Cushman,
她是 DataMade 的一位开发人员
she's a developer at DataMade,
他们一直在努力使城市变得更加开放
where they've been trying to make our cities more open.
将来自政府的大量公开数据进行整理并合理地处理
Reams of open data from governments get compiled and made sensible
就可以让普通市民使用它来采取行动
so ordinary citizens can actually use it and take action.
他们使用的技术是开源的
The tech they use is open source,
同时他们对政治的态度也是如此
but so is their attitude about politics.
我们在芝加哥与一个叫做 City Bureau 的组织
We did a project here in Chicago with a organization called City Bureau
进行了一个项目 和他们一起为公立学校测试铅含量
where we were working with them to get at lead test results for the public schools.
我们测试了这些学校中几乎全部的供水设备
So, the Chicago public schools went through and tested,
这些全部公布的测试结果
if not all, a significant portion of the water fixtures in all of their school and published the results of those tests
有 500 份 PDF 文件之多
as a series of more than 500 PDFs.
是的 这太好了
So, that's great.
但这并不完全是一种使数据公开的有效方式
But it's not exactly an effective way of making data open.
在整个系统中
It was really difficult to see
很难看到例如哪里发现了铅 以及哪里的铅含量更高
where lead was found across the system and, like, higher numbers.
我们使用了另一个叫做 Tablua 的开源工具
We used another open source tool called Tablua,
可以在终端上运行
which you can run from your terminal,
它能从 500 多个 PDF 文件中
to extract data from over 500 PDFs
提取数据并将其放在一起
and put it all together
帮助我们把海量的信息
and help put this huge dump of information
转储到一个对人们有用的上下文中
into a context that was useful for people.
我认为查询源数据是一种非常有效的方式
I think being able to consult that source data is a really powerful way
这使人们可以了解信息的来源
for people to kind of understand where information is coming from
并验证其正确性
and verify that it is, in fact, correct.
市民可以访问健康报告的详细信息
Citizens can access the details of health reports,
获取游说者的数据
data on lobbyists,
还可以查看城市政治的整个组织结构
they get to look at the whole engine of city politics,
DataMade 为此提供了浏览门户
and DataMade opens the hood.
这使芝加哥人有更多机会
That means the people of Chicago have a better chance
对市政的方方面面依民愿作出改变
of bringing about the changes they want to see.
加州州立理工大学的研究软件工程师 Carol Willing 认为
Carol Willing, a research software engineer over at Cal Poly,
这种不断扩展的开源态度
thinks that this expanding open source attitude
将给世界带来更广泛的变化
is the start of something much larger.
就个人而言 我认为开源将从开源软件发展到
Personally, I think that we're gonna evolve beyond open source software
开放硬件、开放政府、
to open hardware, to open government,
开放教育、开放协作、开放创新等等
to open education, open collaboration, innovation,
开源会不断进化
so I think it's gonna continue to evolve.
现在 开源逐渐变得更像是自然法则
Open source is starting to look more like a law of nature
而不仅仅是科技界的产物
than just some outgrowth of the tech world.
人们慷慨奉献自己时间的事迹古而有之
People have been charitable and giving of their time freely for thousands of years,
但令人耳目一新的是
so that's nothing new.
开源深刻地改变了世界
But what is new about open source and has changed the world profoundly
因为它使不同的小群体联合起来
is the ability for groups to work together
一起致力于他们中任何一组都无法单独处理的大型项目
to build something bigger than what they could build on their own.
“用全新的技术来践行古老的理念”——
I love this idea!
这个主意我喜欢!
Taking some very new tech and using it to get back to some very old ideals.
但先别急着高兴
But before we get too excited,
随着开源这个词被越来越广泛地使用
definitions can get wobbly
它的定义可能会变得模糊
as more and more folks start calling themselves open source.
在某些场合下
It starts meaning something that's
它开始意味着“免费” 或者“众包”
just free, or something that's crowdsourced,
甚至仅仅是“可定制”
or even just something that's customizable.
例如
For example,
如果我只是允许你选择在冰淇淋上哪撒些糖粉
if I let you choose what kind of sprinkles go on your ice cream,
这不代表我的冰淇淋是开源甜点
that's not necessarily an open source dessert.
但是 如果我告诉你如何制作糖粉
But if I show you how to make your own sprinkles,
让你改进我的糖粉配方——
let you improve on my sprinkle recipe,
然后 如果你也想与他人分享糖粉制作的秘密
and then give you my blessing if you wanted to share that secret with others,
那么 恭喜你 我们得到了一些美味的开源
now that's some tasty open source right there.
那么 开源的原始定义又是什么？
So, what was that original definition again?
它很简单 但我们应当恪守
It's pretty simple, but we should keep repeating it.
要实现真正的开源
To be truly open source,
你需要公开代码
you need code,
或者蓝图 或者你的菜谱
or a blueprint, or a recipe.
换句话说
In other words,
就是使任何人都可以随意研究、
some kind of raw data that anyone can study,
修改和重新分发原始数据
change, and redistribute at will.
这种哲学将带来变革
It's a philosophy that's just starting to revolutionize the world
不过对于命令行外的世界 一切才刚刚开始
beyond our command lines.
*BGM*
这是一种非常惊人的技术开发方式
It's a really phenomenal way to do technology,
无论是它的成功
and I'm thrilled to death that is has been as successful
还是我已经参与其中的这一事实 都让我感到震惊
as it has been and that I've gotten to be a part of it.
Thomas Cameron
Thomas Cameron has been involved in open source
在 1998 年“开源”这个词被发明之前就一直从事开源工作。
since before the term was coined in 1998.
今天 他是 Red Hat 的高级首席云推广人员
Today, he's senior principal cloud evangelist at Red Hat.
他完全有资格谈论开源在如今的进展
He's perfectly positioned to talk about how far open source has come,
以及其发展的过程中发究竟生了多少斗争
but also how many battles were fought along the way.
你知道 经理们不想承担风险
Man there is huge pushback, you know, managers didn't want to take on the risk
这是巨大的阻力 因为它是免费的
because, well, it's free;
所以他们会想 “我没办法打电话寻求技术支持”
there's no one that I can pick up the phone and call for support;
“我不得不依靠特定的开源软件”之类
I have to depend on you.
这一类斗争还算简单
But we won a lot of these sort-of-easy fights,
在部门服务器、群组服务器、
the departmental servers or divisional servers
小型 Web 服务器、小型文件服务器和打印服务器上
or a small web server, a small file and print server,
随着时间的推移，我们打了不少胜仗
and over time after winning these easier fights,
更艰难的战斗出现了
the tougher ones came along.
在每次“作战”中 你会发现
And with every single one of those, you saw
系统管理员和系统工程师对开源越来越着迷
sysadmins and systems engineers become more enamored of open source.
长风破浪会有时 直挂云帆济沧海
Despite these battles, you couldn't deny the ongoing progress.
我目睹了开源给 IT 行业带来的改变
I have been able to watch open source transform the IT industry,
它最开始时用在
and it’s gone from
某些系统管理员办公桌下私搭乱建的服务器里
that rogue server that some sysadmin had under his desk
并最终传播到家喻户晓的大公司之中——英特尔、IBM、AMD
to huge companies with household names—Intel, IBM, AMD,
哎 你懂的
you know,
每个你能想到的组织都开始为开源项目做出贡献
every organization you can imagine has started contributing to open source projects.
这绝对是一场斗争
And it was absolutely a fight,
我在不同的企业职位上都参加过如此多的相关争论
there were so many arguments I had at various enterprise positions that I held
我曾说过
where I said,
“我们需要把 Linux或其他开源技术引入数据中心”
"You know, we need to introduce Linux® or other open source technologies into the datacenter."
Thomas 观察到 开源软件开发正逐步占据市场
Thomas sees that open source software development is taking over.
但对于某些人来说 这很令人不安
But for some people, that's pretty unsettling.
我们能够分享信息与分析结果
We're able to share information and analysis,
这让那些一直占有信息并从中牟利的人感到害怕
and so that scares folks who historically have been the ones to hold information and derive value from it,
这种模式使他们无法轻易获取利润
whether it's charging money
也难以哪怕得到对一个组织的完全控制
or just having control of an organization,
这是巨大的变化 随之而来的是恐惧
it's a huge change and with that comes fear.
我们在本季开始时描述的支持开源的反叛者们
The open source rebels that we described at the start of the season
正领导着这个行业
have now become industry leaders.
但从更长远的角度来看 故事绝不会在这里结束
But that's not the end of the story, not by a long shot.
Christopher Tozzi 是Fixate IO的高级编辑
Christopher Tozzi is the senior editor at Fixate IO.
他将开源带来的颠覆视为某种根本性转变的开始
He sees open source disruption as the start of a fundamental shift in the way people everywhere,
这种转变将使世界各地的人们都能协同合作 - 而不仅是在软件开发行业中
not just software, are going to work together.
我认为 在过去的二十年里 开源变得如此强大的原因之一
I think that one of the things that has made open source so powerful over the last two decades
就是人们对去中心化一直保有兴趣
is this continued interest in decentralization.
我认为，这也解释了开源如何影响其它技术创新
I think this also speaks to how open source has influenced other technological innovations.
比如 区块链也建立在这样的思想上：
Things like blockchain, which is also founded centrally on the ideas that databases,
如果我们摆脱集中的生产方式
or example, or transactions could be more efficient or could be more secure if they're decentralized,
去中心化的数据库或交易方式可能会更高效、更安全
if we get away from centralized modes of production.
重申一次 我认为今天的开源
And again, open source I think today,
自从 Torvalds 出现以来
ever since Torvalds came along,
就与开发工作的去中心化息息相关
had been about decentralization of development in labor basically.
全面的分权
That decentralization across the board
意味着整个世界都在走向开源
means the whole world's going open source.
体现了这一理念的开发人员
The developers who embody that philosophy,
他们是最能想象未来的人
they're the ones who have the best shot at imagining that future.
这是 Tristram Oaten
Here's Tristram Oaten,
他是伦敦的一位开发者
he's a developer based in London,
他肯定在考虑这场漫长的比赛
and he's definitely thinking about that long game.
就像是3D打印机将通过在家生产零件来使我们的生活更轻松
It looks like 3D printers are going to make our lives easier
而且多半能更环保一样
and hopefully more ecologically sound by producing parts at home.
无论什么时候有东西坏了 你都可以在家里新制造一个
Whenever something breaks, you can just make it at home.
这是星际迷航式的未来的复制器
It's the ideal Star Trek replicator future
就和理想中一模一样
that we were promised so very long ago.
这样 说不定 整座房子都能变得开源了
Hopefully, that will come into play so that entire houses can perhaps be open source.
Tristram设想了一个世界
Tristram imagines a world
在这个世界上，开源是各个领域都遵守的规则
where open source is the rule of the land
这意味着
and that means developers become,
开发者即使不是大师 至少也会成为人们的向导
if not gurus, then at least guides.
这种向导是至关重要的
Really critical guides.
在未来 我们作为开发人员的角色将越加重要
In the future, our role as developers is going to become increasingly more and more important,
我们会变得越来越像“魔法师”
and it's going to get increasingly more and more like wizards
如果我们现在还不够像的话
if it isn't already.
好吧 魔法师
Okay, wizards.
我们会成为魔法师
We'll be wizards.
我们能用奇怪的语言驱使机器做奇妙的事
We speak strange languages that make these machines do wonderful things,
于是 我们会被高薪雇来做宫廷魔法师
and we're paid a lot of money to be the court wizard,
或者公司魔法师
or the company wizard.
每个人的身体中都有设备
And when there are devices in everyone's bodies and when there are devices everywhere
并且无处不在的设备都可以通过互联网访问
that are internet-accessible
还能被远程控制时
and can be remote-controlled,
我们则需要作为一个团体
it's going to be very important that we as a group,
一个行会 以最好的信念行事
as a guild, act in best faith,
就像医疗行业要有不伤害他人的宪章等等 这非常重要
that the medical profession has a charter to do no harm and so forth.
我认为 开发人员需要共同决定
I think that as developers, we need to collectively decide
不要制造杀手机器人
that we're not going to build the killer robots,
也不要在每个人的路由器和每个人的助听器中
we're not going to build spying software
安置间谍软件
into everyone's router and everybody's hearing aides.
我们需要彼此确认
We need to assure each other,
并向所有人保证
and assure everyone,
我们将为更大的利益而努力
that we're going to work for the greater good,
而非为了伤害人类
and not against humanity.
*BGM*
让我们现在保证不会造机器人杀手 对吧？
Let's all just promise right now that we won't build killer robots,
好
Okay.
在此之上 我确实认为 Tristram 说得对
And beyond that, I do think Tristram's on to something.
在某些方面
In some ways,
我们开发者已经看到了未来
we developers have seen the future
这代表我们有机会在塑造未来上出一份力
and that means we've got a chance to help shape it.
10 年后 开源开发的道德标准将会是什么样子的？
What are the ethics of open source development going to look like in 10 years?
我们现在有着极大的特权
We're in a supremely privileged position,
因此 我们有责任做正确的事
and it's up to us to do the right thing.
*BGM*
那么魔法师们 我们将去向何方？
So, wizards, where are we heading?
我们能为开源创造一个健康的未来吗？
Can we conjure up a healthy future for open source?
我想和一个对这一切进行了深入思考的人谈谈
I wanted to talk with someone who's done some deep thinking about all of this,
于是 我找到了这一位
and I found her.
Safia Abdall 是一名软件工程师
Safia Abdalla is a software engineer
她一直在为交互计划做开源贡献
who's been making open source contributions to the Interact Project.
我们将会讨论
We started imagining
真正的、可持续的、广泛的开源世界
what a real, sustainable, broad-reaching open source world
会是什么样子
could look like.
听听看
Have a listen.
在你心里未来的开源会是怎么样的？
When you think about the future of open source and what that looks like,
和现在有什么不同之处？
what are some differences we might see?
嗯我想 我所看到的最大的新兴趋势之一
Yeah, so I think one of the biggest emerging trends
就是对开源可持续性的高度关注
that I'm seeing is a lot of focus on open source sustainability,
我认为在该领域已经有了许多有趣的进展
And I think there's been a lot of interesting progress in that space.
*BGM*
我们的工作能够得到多少改善？
how much better could our work become?
又会发生多少变化
How much would change?
如果我们能够建立她所描述的可持续发展的方法
If we could build that sustainable approach she's describing,
如果公司能够贡献时间、代码和资源，我们的工作能够得到多少改善？
if corporations were contributing time, code, and resources.
所以我问她
So I asked her,
这样可持续的方式会给我们所创造的产品
how do you see that impacting that actual products we create
和我们建构的工具 带来怎么样的改变？
and the tools that we build?
可悲的现实是
The sad reality is that
当你没有精力 时间和金钱来为每个人打造好东西时
when you don't have the focus and time and energy and money to build something well for everyone,
你就会倾向于只为自己做好它
what you tend to do is just build it well for yourself.
嗯 确实
Mm-hmm (affirmative), absolutely.
因此我相信开放源码模型 才能延长其生命周期
So I believe that if we discover more sustainable model for open source,
那么我们实际上将开始构建
we're actually gonna start building software that's accessible to individuals
可供盲人、听障者或以其它方式残障的个人使用的软件
who might be blind, or hard of hearing, or disabled in other ways.
有趣 我喜欢
Interesting, yeah I really like that.
考虑到开放源代码的原则、流程、文化和社区
So, when you think about how the principles and processes and culture and community
以及你提到的所有这些内容
and all those things you mentioned of
该如何适用于技术之外、软件开发之外的行业时
open source might be applied to industries outside of technology, outside of software development,
你认为真正可以从开源中受益的领域是哪些？
what are some fields that you think could really benefit from open source,
你认为接下来开源可能会出现在哪里？
and where do you think open source might show up next?
喔 这是个有趣的角度
Oh that's a really interesting observation.
我第一个想到的是，开源思维可以被用于科学界
The immediate answer that comes to me is an open source mindset in the science community
使科学变得更加开放
and open science.
之所以我会想到这一点是因为
I think the realization is that
当你以开放方式分享软件时
when you share software in an open fashion,
你所分享的并不是一行行的代码
what you're sharing is not the literal lines of code,
好吧你确实在分享代码
well that is what you're sharing,
但更重要的是
but the other thing that you're sharing on top of that
你在分享知识和细节 在与其他人交流该如何做事
is knowledge and details about how to do something.
因此你真正分享的是知识
So what you're really sharing is knowledge.
开源的方式可以相当直接地应用于科学界
That translates really directly to the scientific world
因为研究人员也会花费大量的时间来探究特定课题
where researchers will spend a lot of time exploring a particular topic
随后就此课题发表论文
and then publish a research paper on it.
而且我认为我们需要向科学界倡议更加开放的科研方式
And I think focusing on an open science initiative
以确保科研成果能够对所有人开放
that makes sure that researchers are producing work that is accessible to all people,
以确保科研成果能够对所有人开放，使所有人都能理解、分享和参与
understandable by all people, and shareable and extendable by all people
这将会提高社会对科学的理解
is gonna improve society's understanding of science
并在一定程度上促进科学研究本身
and how far we can push research forward.
当我上大学时 我从事生物化学研究
When I was in college, I did biochemistry research
我非常习惯于带着热情进行实验、研究、尝试新事物
and I was very much used to this passion for experimenting, for researching, for trying new things,
然而同时 你也不能让人随意插手研究
but at the same time still being very protective over your discoveries
因为你需要称为通讯作者
because you need to be a published author.
（注：存在学术流氓！）
你需要信誉
You need credit,
这是学术界进步的一个很重要、很重要的组成部分
You need credit, that is a huge, huge part of moving up in academia.
因此，开源的原则
So, when we're talking about bringing these open source principles
即分享原始数据、贡献劳动以及将未完成的产品公之于众
of sharing and contributing and putting out unfinished products out there and hoping other people will fill it in,
依靠集体智慧将其完工的这些原则
how do you see those principles possibly
和某些更具保护意识的行业必然发生冲突
colliding in other industries
你如何看待这种冲突？
where people might be more protective?
这是个好问题 我认为这涉及一个更大、更复杂的问题
Yeah, that's a great question, and I think that touches on a way hairier, bigger problem.
为了成功地将开源引入其他行业
For open source to be successful,
外在的动机和鼓励在很大程度上是必要的
the motivations and the incentives have to be,
你不能依赖于鼓励人们只专注于自己的目标的现有体系
You can't rely on systems that encourage people to focus on their own goals and motivations at the expense of others,
因为那样会牺牲他人的利益和社会的更大利好
and at the expense of the greater good of society.
我认为我们必须根本地改变我们看待很多事情的方式
I think at a fundamental level, we have to restructure the way we see a lot of things
并更改许多体系的运作方式
and the way a lot of systems work to have them focus on
很难撤销像终身教职这样对大学有很多负面影响的制度
It's hard to do, it's hard to undo systems, like tenure, which have a lot of negative repercussions at universities.
很难消除其它可能损害生态、损害他人 或者阻碍社会进步的激励机制
It's hard to undo other incentive systems that can harm the planet, can harm other people, can harm progress as a society.
不管是采用开源的思维方式
But starting to adopt an open source mindset
还是主动取消这些体系
and taking the initiative to begin to undo those systems
我们都有极长的路要走
will go a long way.
(注：害人之心不可有，防人之心不可无: l)
确实
Absolutely,
如果你可以从头重新创造开源
so if you could recreate open source in its entirety from scratch,
那么 属于你的开源版本又会是什么样的？
what would your version of open source look like?
哇噻 *来自Abdalla的奸笑~*
关于开源 我要改变的第一件事
The first thing that I would change about open source
是它的公共关系和形象
is its public relations and its image.
我可能会尝试建立一种开源文化或社区
I would probably attempt to build an open source culture or community
让人们认识到
that didn't issue that perception
你即使不是精英 或者精湛的开发人员 也能活跃并取得成功
that you had to be elite or a fantastic developer in order to thrive and succeed,
现有开源文化中的精英倾向使我感到震慑
and that was one of the biggest things that deterred me.
另外 我也要重点关注开源的可持续性
The other big thing I would focus on is open source sustainability,
增加公司的责任感和开源体系的健康程度
increasing corporate accountability and the health of open source systems.
我认为很多人没有意识到的事情之一是
I think one of the things that a lot of people don't realize
许多受欢迎的技术公司和平台都包含了开源要素
is that a lot of really popular technology companies and platforms that people use are mostly comprised of open source.
例如 有很多Rails Web 应用程序是极其成功的 盈利能力可观
S:恩 确实
Like, how many Rails web applications are super profitable and successful now.
Enhmmm, absolutely.
而且我认为 对我们来说重要的是
And I think it's important for us to
确保这些公司对开源社区有管理权
ensure that those corporations have a stewardship to the open source community
认识到其价值所在
and recognize where their value is,
并给予回馈
and contribute it back.
好的 在 Safia 的开源中
Okay, so in Safia's open source
我们将其称为S.O.S
we'll call it S.O.S.
企业将会负起责任
we have corporate accountability,
并对开源的可持续性做出贡献
and corporations contributing to the sustainability of open source.
项目的贡献者和维护者可能会因为自己所做的工作而获得报酬
We have contributors and maintainers possibly being paid themselves for the work that they do,
这样的开源多半会是更加开放、更具有关怀之心的模式
and generally a more loving and open brand for what open source is.
是的
Yeah.
听起来像是一个很棒的开源的版本 我喜欢它
Sounds like a great version of open source, I like it.
谢谢
Thank you.
Safia Abdalla 是交互计划的软件工程师和贡献者
Safia Abdalla is a software engineer and a contributor to the Interact Project.
她是一位新一代开发人员
She's part of a new generation of developers.
而她在平时也对开源抱有自己的期望
But even she's coming at it with the expectation of open source by default,
所以，我想向这支新的代码英雄军队大声呼喊
so I wanna give a shout out to that new army of command line heroes.
“你们都将会向我们展示未来，
You all are going to show us the future.
因为你们现在正生活在未来之中，
You're living it right now.
而你们也将负责领导我们走向明天。”
You're going to lead the charge.
*欢呼声*
*BGM*
现在 尽管我对开源革命心怀热情
Now as excited as I am for the open source revolution,
但我也不想成为一个盲目乐观的人
I don't wanna be a Pollyanna either.
开源也将会受到挑战
There are going to be challenges.
开源的存在越广泛
The bigger open source gets,
我们就越需要确保它的可持续性
the more we have to make sure that it's actually sustainable.
我们找到了一种可扩展的方式来维护开源项目吗？
Have we honestly figured out a scalable way of maintaining open source projects?
我的意思是 虽然 Linux 内核的贡献者中有一些是全职员工
I mean, the Linux kernels got some contributors who are full-time employees,
但是大多数的开源项目仍然是由志愿者维护的
but most of the open source projects out there are still maintained by volunteers.
开源的工作并不会因为我们不再“反叛”而终结
The work of open source isn't over just because we've graduated from rebel status.
市值数十亿美元的公司都在运行 Linux
Multi-billion dollar companies are running on Linux,
而开源先锋们现在是技术领袖
open source pioneers are now tech leaders,
我们需要跟随这条道路
we need to track this trajectory
并试着想象接下来会发生什么
and try to imagine what comes next.
尤其是 可能会出现什么问题
In particular, what could go wrong?
Christopher Tozzi 告诉我们
Christopher Tozzi describes how open source,
曾经作为规则破坏者的开源并不对破坏本身免疫
once the disruptor, is not vulnerable to disruption itself.
开源革命尚未结束
The open source revolution is not over,
因为挑战并没有停止
because it's not as if the challenges are going to stop coming.
即使今天基本上地球上每个使用计算机的人
Even though today basically everybody on the planet who uses a computer
都在以这样或那样的方式使用开源软件
is using open source in one way or another,
但这并不代表开源必然是绝对安全的
that doesn't mean that open source is necessarily totally safe from disruption.
尤其是从致力于开源社区最初目标的人们的角度来看
Especially from the perspective of people who are committed to the original goals of the open source communities,
诸如云计算之类的事物确实使情况变得复杂了
which things like cloud computing really complicate in certain ways.
开源能有多开源呢？
How open source will open source be?
Christopher提到了云计算
Christopher mentioned cloud computing
而在第六集中
and in Episode 6,
我们描述了依赖于别人的数据中心
we described how becoming reliant on somebody else's datacenter
肯定会使开源最初的目标复杂化
definitely complicates the original goals of open source.
这是一个棘手的领域
It's tricky territory,
我们仍在了解这个领域的情况
and we're still learning the lay of the land.
在前进的过程中，
As we move forward,
我们必须不忘初心
we're gonna have to remind ourselves about our roots.
每个年轻的反叛者都需要欧比旺·克诺比的原力全息仪
Every young rebel needs that Obi Wan hologram moment.
他们会从过去吸取经验教训吗？
Will they get a reminder from the past?
林纳斯·托瓦兹Linus Torvalds曾经说过
Here's what our Linus Torvalds once said,
“在真正的开源中，你有权掌握自己的命运。”
"In real open source, you have the right to control your own destiny."
如果开发人员能够在更大的世界中宣扬这种精神
If developers helped to encourage that spirit in the bigger world,
那么 干得漂亮
that's a pretty good job.
到此为止 这是第一季的最后一集
So, this is the final episode of Season 1.
真不敢相信
Can you believe it?
这一季过得真快
This season just flew by.
在着手编写这一系列播客之前
Before working on this podcast,
我从没有想过 是谁创造了 DevOps、敏捷开发和云计算
things like DevOps, agile, and cloud, I didn't really think about where they came from,
我从没有想过它们从何而来
and who made them.
我从没想过它们会有自己的家
I never thought they had homes
有团队贡献才能、照顾它们
with teams and talent who cared for them
帮助它们成长
and helped them grow.
们只是我工具箱里的一堆工具
They were just a bunch of tools in my toolbox.
但我现在不是这样看待它们的
But that's not how I see them now.
它们不仅仅是随机的工具
They're not just random tools,
而是我生活环境的一部分
they're a part of the landscape I live in.
在我之前 开发者们已经花了几十年的时间来塑造这一局面
A landscape the developers who came before me have been shaping for decades.
现在 我要致力于塑造未来
Now, I get to help shape what comes next.
真是棒极了
That's amazing.
*BGM*
第一季即将结束
Season 1 may be coming to a close,
但好消息是 我们已经在准备第二季了
but good news, we're already working on Season 2.
在这七集中
Over these past 7 episodes,
我们专注于开源工具和方法论
we focused on the open source tools and methodologies
这些工具和方法使我们有了今天
that brought us to where we are today.
这有点像是从 3 万英尺的高度看开源世界的形成史
Sort of like the 30,000-foot view of how the open source world came to be.
在第二季中 我们将着眼于细节
In Season 2, we're going to zoom in
并关注当今代码英雄们史诗般的奋斗
and focus on the epic struggles of today's command line heroes.
我们将跟随每一集 看看开发者如何挑战常规
We get to tag along each episode and see how developers on the ground are challenging the norm.
这些都是塑造我们行业未来的真实故事
These are the real life stories that shape the future of our industry.
当我们寻找这些故事的时候
And while we hunt those stories down,
我们很希望收到您的来信
we'd love to heard from you.
告诉我们 你的代码故事是什么？
Tell us, what's your command line story?
你参与过哪些史诗般的开源战役？
What epic open source battles have you been waging?
访问 redhat.com/command-line-heroes 留下你的故事
Go to redhat.com/command-line-heroes to drop your story.
我们正在倾听
We're listening.
如果现在你还在听的话
While you're there,
你可能想要看看
you might want to check out the lineup
s将于 5 月 8 日至 10 日在旧金山举行的 2018 红帽峰会的阵容
for the 2018 Red Hat Summit happening in San Francisco May 8-10.
峰会包括为期三天的
Three days of
分组会议、动手实验和主题演讲，其中包括了有关开源的主题演讲
breakout sessions, hands-on labs, and keynotes including one from yours truly all about open source.
希望能在那里见到你
Hope to see you there.
代码英雄是红帽的原创播客
Command Line Heroes is an original podcast from Red Hat.
请确保你订阅了该节目 以在您的设备上免费获取第一季中的所有剧集
To get all of the episodes from Season 1 delivered to your device for free
并在第二季开始时收到通知
and to get notified for the start of Season 2,
只要在苹果播客、Spotify、Google Play、CastBox 和其他播客平台中搜索《代码英雄》
make sure to subscribe to the show.
然后点击订阅
你就可以第一时间收听新一期
or however you get your podcasts.
我是 Saron Yitbarek
I'm Saron Yitbarek,
感谢你的聆听 编程不止
thanks for listening, and keep on coding!
*BGM*